[
  {
    "id": 3342,
    "questionText": "If the base sequence in DNA is 5' AAAT 3' then the base sequence in mRNA is :",
    "option1": "5'UUUU3'",
    "option2": "3'UUUU5'",
    "option3": "5'AAAU3'",
    "option4": "3'AAAU5'",
    "correctAnswer": "5'AAAU3'",
    "timeLimit": 30
  },
  {
    "id": 3315,
    "questionText": "Avery, MacLeod and Mc Carty used the S(virulent) and R (avirulent) strains of streptococcus pneumoniae. They isolated and purified protein, DNA, RNA from the bacteria and treated them with related enzymes. They concluded that :",
    "option1": "DNA was transforming agent",
    "option2": "RNA was transforming agent",
    "option3": "Protein was transforming agent",
    "option4": "All are correct",
    "correctAnswer": "DNA was transforming agent",
    "timeLimit": 30
  },
  {
    "id": 3381,
    "questionText": "Identify the characteristic which is not applicable to the genetic code:",
    "option1": "Non-Polar",
    "option2": "Non-Overlapping",
    "option3": "Commaless",
    "option4": "Universal",
    "correctAnswer": "Non-Polar",
    "timeLimit": 30
  },
  {
    "id": 3295,
    "questionText": "Ribose is differentiable from deoxyribose in having :",
    "option1": "Two extra oxygen",
    "option2": "No oxygen",
    "option3": "Hydroxyl group at 2nd carbon",
    "option4": "One extra hydrogen",
    "correctAnswer": "Hydroxyl group at 2nd carbon",
    "timeLimit": 30
  },
  {
    "id": 3356,
    "questionText": "A DNA strand is directly involved in the synthesis of all the following except:",
    "option1": "Another DNA",
    "option2": "t-RNA & m-RNA",
    "option3": "r-RNA",
    "option4": "Protein",
    "correctAnswer": "Protein",
    "timeLimit": 30
  },
  {
    "id": 3343,
    "questionText": "The genes are responsible for growth and differentiation in an organism through regulation of :",
    "option1": "Translocation",
    "option2": "Transformation",
    "option3": "Transduction and translation",
    "option4": "Translation and transcription",
    "correctAnswer": "Translation and transcription",
    "timeLimit": 30
  },
  {
    "id": 3316,
    "questionText": "Genetic information is carried out by long chain molecule made up of :",
    "option1": "Amino acids",
    "option2": "Enzymes",
    "option3": "Nucleotides",
    "option4": "Histone proteins",
    "correctAnswer": "Nucleotides",
    "timeLimit": 30
  },
  {
    "id": 3376,
    "questionText": "Anticodons are found in:",
    "option1": "mRNA",
    "option2": "tRNA",
    "option3": "rRNA",
    "option4": "In all",
    "correctAnswer": "tRNA",
    "timeLimit": 30
  },
  {
    "id": 3302,
    "questionText": "Which of the following element is not found in nitrogenous base :",
    "option1": "Nitrogen",
    "option2": "Hydrogen",
    "option3": "Carbon",
    "option4": "Phosphorus",
    "correctAnswer": "Phosphorus",
    "timeLimit": 30
  },
  {
    "id": 3378,
    "questionText": "Transfer of genetic information from a polymer of nucleotides to a polymer of amino acids is:",
    "option1": "Replication",
    "option2": "Transcription",
    "option3": "Translation",
    "option4": "Reverse transcription",
    "correctAnswer": "Translation",
    "timeLimit": 30
  }
]